CURRICULUM VITAE

Name Mallikarjun Tirlapur

Date of birth **22.04.1988**Telephone **+919740003234**

E-mail <u>tirlapurmallikarjun@gmail.com</u>

Website https://mallikarjuntirlapur.github.io/

Address #28, 1st B Main Road, Mohan Kumar Nagar, Yeshwanthpur,

560022, Bengaluru, India

OBJECTIVE

A Challenging position that allows me to continuously engage with and adapt to new technologies. I am committed to leveraging my skills and expertise to drive innovation and contribute to the continued success of the organization.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Embedded Security Software Developer,

01.02.2016 -

Staff Embedded Software Developer,

Senior Staff Embedded Software Developer

Infineon Technologies AG, Augsburg / Bengaluru.

- Expert in embedded secure software development, developing Java Card Operating System in a scrum team.
- Designed and developed a high-performance and secure Java Card Virtual Machine in native embedded C.
- Created threat models, secure coding patterns, and implemented countermeasures against potential attacks.
- Developed well documented **I2C** low-level drivers and JC API native interfaces.
- Implemented Cryptographic **SHA** algorithm native interfaces, enhancing the platform's cryptographic capabilities.
- Architected and implemented memory management algorithms for handling objects in memory.
- Conceptualized and successfully led a team of 4 in the development of a Java Card binary linker tool.
- Implemented over 50 Java Card Virtual Machine bytecodes, enhancing the platform's functionality and security.
- Defined memory layout for the OS and architected memory access permissions by programming MPU.
- Automated MPU configurations, reducing developer effort by 50% and improving overall efficiency.
- Configured **ARM TrustZone**, enabling secure and non-secure worlds for OS and sandbox apps, respectively.
- Introduced and implemented **10+** innovative ideas, reducing code footprint by **~40 KB** and substantially improving system performance.
- Developed production tools in collaboration with the production team by translating high-level architecture into component-level design.
- Led team development by conducting trainings, mentoring freshers, hiring and guiding interns, and presenting work to stakeholders for alignment and visibility.
- Developed comprehensive white box and black box tests, enhancing software quality assurance and reliability.
- Created automation tools using Python scripting, streamlining daily software CI processes.
- Developed java card applets, unit tests and fixed bugs.
- **Patent Filed** (Pending):
 - 1. "A method of improving Java card VM performance of the java card product." (increased by 150%)
 - 2. "Alias for package-info in import component of CAP file." (90% package-info footprint saving)

Embedded Developer

01.11.2015 - 31-01-2016

COBI-Connected Biking for everyone, Frankfurt.

- Developed tasks on FreeRTOS, programming PWM for driving RGB channels of LED light of the bike.
- Procured knowledge in CAN bus e-bike driver development.

Master Thesis

01.04.2015 - 30.09.2015

KUKA Roboter GmbH, R&D Technology Development, Augsburg.

Research Topic: A framework for non-expert robot programming facilitated by a self-localizing smart device.

Objective: A smart device (Project Tango Smartphone) equipped with high-end sensing capabilities facilitates the programming of industrial robots in the field of logistic tasks such as pick-and-place and packaging.

- Developed an android app to publish on touch 2D pixel coordinates.
- Developed algorithms in C++ on ROS platform to locate objects.
- Developed a base station program for processing images using computer vision state-of-the-art algorithm APIs.

Internship

01.09.2014 - 28.02.2015

KUKA Roboter GmbH, R&D Technology Development, Augsburg.

Research Project: Developing pick-and-place robotic applications using Project Tango Smartphone on ROS

- Developed an android app from scratch to parse super frames for depth & RGB images and publish live images into ROS network over wireless network (Wi-Fi).
- Developed 2D to 3D transformation algorithm.

Application Engineer

05.07.2010 - 19.08.2013

Microchip Technology Private Ltd (INDIA), Bangalore.

- Post-silicon validation of PIC microcontroller peripherals by writing various tests in C.
- Developed magnetic stripe reader prototype for customers.
- Answering internal and external customer queries.

EDUCATION

Hochschule Darmstadt,	Master's in electrical engineering
Germany	System Design (C++ & UML), Technical Project Management, Design and Test
Sep 2013 – Feb 2016	of Microelectronic Systems, Complex Digital Architectures, Advanced Feedback
	Control, Advanced Automation, and Advanced Robotics.
The National Institute Of	Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Communications Engineering
Engineering, Mysore	Basic and advanced Mathematics, C, C++, Logic Design, Image processing,
Sep 2006 - June 2010	Electronic Circuits and Design, Digital Signal Processing, Analog and Digital
	Communication, Microcontrollers, Microprocessors. Embedded Systems

SKILLS

General: Leadership, Requirement Analysis, Design, Architecture, Secure Software Development, Debugging, Testing

Operating Systems: Java Card OS, FreeRTOS, and Embedded Linux concepts.

Programming Languages: C, C++, Python, Java, C#, Assembly.

Microcontrollers & Processors: ARM Cortex-M/A, PIC microcontrollers.

Microcontroller fundamentals: MPU, MMU, Timers, PWM, DMA, WDT, ADC, DAC.

Communication Buses: SPI, I2C, RS-232, and CAN.

IDEs: Keil uVision, Eclipse, VS Code, Visual Studio, Android Studio, MPLAB 8, and MPLAB X.

Software tools: ARM Toolchain, JavaCard Toolchain, MS Office Tools, Git, Doxygen, BitBucket, Jenkins, LabVIEW. **Lab Equipments:** Agilent &Tektronix Oscilloscope, Function generator, Digital multi-meters, DC Power supply,

Thermonics, Soldering.

Languages: English & Hindi (native proficiency), German (B1), and Kannada (mother tongue).

VOLUNTEERING

- Member of Toastmasters Club
- Teacher at eVidyaloka(not-for-profit organisation) Trust

PERSONAL TRAITS

- Quick learner, adaptable to new technologies.
- Self-motivated and proactive in driving projects and teams.
- Strong resource management skills with proven ability to deliver results.

HOBBIES

Yoga, Table tennis, Biking and Hiking.